CHRISTOPHER BOOTH

CONTENT PRODUCER AND EDITOR

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am a radio and multimedia producer with 4+ years of experience in the industry. I take pride in my abilities to produce quality content and to communicate with children, parents, healthcare workers and communities. At the moment, I would love to further my passions in the realm of writing, publishing and coding.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

October 2017-Present | RX Radio, Cape Town

Content Producer

- Trained and coached over 80 Child and Young Reporters in radio and writing skills.
- Produced educational content for over 6 monthly shows and over 200 health-related podcasts.
- Developing Children's Rights in Hospital Charter to be adopted by Red Cross War Memorial Children's Hospital.
- Collaborated with various partners for syndications, such as Bush Radio, Nal'iBali, Sea Harvest, NEMISA, etc.
- Writer and copy editor for RX Radio's social media, newsletter and blog (brand awareness)
- Winner of the 2020 WHO Reboot Health and Wellbeing Challenge.

February 2018 – December 2018 | The Harry Crossley Children's Nursing Development Unit, Cape Town

Communications Specialist

- Interviewed over 10 nursing students from various countries in Africa about their experiences.
- Wrote articles and content for CNDU's website.
- Created social media posts and content for public relation purposes.

June 2015 – August 2017 | GABA Corporation, Tokyo, Japan English Instructor

- Taught adults and teenagers English in one-on-on lessons.
- Taught a variation of Business English and Casual English.
- Conducted First Lessons for individuals wanting English lessons.

- +2772 336 2004
- chris.booth.ct@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/chris-w-booth/
- chrisboothct.wix.com/portfolio

EDUCATION

April 2016

Rhodes University, Grahamstown, South Africa

Master of Arts: Health Journalism
Thesis title: "Creating evidence-based
guidelines for healthy eating
educational campaigns aimed at lowincome South Africans: a case study of
Grahamstown"

April 2013

Rhodes University, Grahamstown, South Africa

Bachelor of Journalism, Honors equivalent: cum laude

RELEVANT SKILLS

Adobe Creative Suite (primarily Audition and Premiere)

Audio and Video Editing

Training children and adults

Working with children and communities

Academic research

June 2015 – August 2017 | Booth In Japan, Tokyo, Japan Blogger (Writer and Video Editor)

- Created a travel blog for visitors to Japan.
- Wrote blog posts on a variety of topics, including travel information, Japanese culture, Japanese life.
- Produced videos featuring visual clips from my travels around the country.

February 2017 – August 2017 | GABA Corporation, Tokyo, Japan Video Podcast Actor

- Acted in a variety of video podcasts that taught English to Japanese speakers.
- Hosted a number of the video podcasts with a Japanese co-host.
- Completed two batches of 10 videos over the course of 6 months.

February 2012 – November 2014 | Rhodes University, Grahamstown, South Africa

Broadcast Tutor and Writing Intensive Tutor

- Led three groups of Second Year Journalism students to produce their own radio shows.
- Gave guidance and feedback to students in their radio programming.
- Gave guidance and feedback to Second Year Journalism students with regards to their academic essays.

ACHIEVEMENTS & LEADERSHIP

- WHO Reboot Health and Wellbeing Challenge Winner Children's Voices During COVID-19 (2020)
- Head of Internal Audience Research at RX Radio (2018-present)
- Editor of RX Radio's Newsletter (2019-present)
- Lead training facilitator at Brooklyn Chest RX Radio (April 2021 basic training)

REFERENCES

- Noluyolo Ngomani, Station Manager, RX Radio statiomanager@rxradio.co.za / +27 73 262 0953
- Dr Gabriel Urgoiti, Founder, RX Radio gabs@rxradio.co.za / +27 82 465 2971
- Jenya Masahiro, Manager, GABA Corporation jmashiro@gaba.co.jp
- Harry Dugmore, Masters Supervisor, Rhodes University h.dugmore@ru.az.za / +27 82 885 7537
- Jeanne Du Toit, Journalism Lecturer, Rhodes University j.dutoit@ru.ac.za / +27 83 573 9970